And now we'll go a bit faster through the other models.
이제 다른 모델들을 좀 더 빠르게 비춰볼게요
We'll start with Google's Gemini.
구글의 쌍둥이자리부터 시작하죠
I have the Pro plan and I can pick between Gemini Advanced and and flash.
프로 플랜이 있어요 제미니 어드밴스드와 플래시 중 고를 수 있죠
And let's what should we do.
어떻게 할까요?
Let's let's ask it the, the uh, first of all, the question about the whimsical question about how
질문을 해 보죠 우선, 기발한 질문이에요 하와이에서
many rainbows does it take to jump all the way from Hawaii?
저 멀리까지 뛰려면 무지개가 몇 개나 필요할까요?
17.
17살요
And let's see, uh, let's see how it, uh, handles the the answer to this.
이 문제에 대한 답을 어떻게 처리하는지 보죠
Uh, so, uh, you can see, um, that it's given an answer which, whilst it's fine, um, it's, um,
여기 답이 나온 걸 볼 수 있어요 괜찮긴 한데 너무
it's definitely overly literal.
뻔하죠
It's certainly not got the kind of response that we got from GPT that's so clearly understood.
GPT에서 받은 반응은 확실히 명확하게 이해되지 않았죠
The, the, the fact that we were being humorous with the question and was able to work with it in a
그 질문을 유머러스하게 던지고 장난스럽게 다룰 수
playful way.
있었어요
So it to me, this sort of shows the slight lack of of nuance, ability to understand the meaning behind
제가 보기엔 뉘앙스가 부족하고 이런 말의 의미를 이해할 능력이 부족하지만 제미니
something like this, but it is still a thorough answer from Gemini.
계획의 완벽한 답이에요
Let's ask it how many times have a new chat?
물어보죠 새 채팅이 몇 번이죠?
How many times does the letter A appear in this sentence?
A가 이 문장에 몇 번이나 나오죠?
And let's see how it can handle that.
어떻게 대처하는지 보죠
It's thinking.
생각 중이에요
So that's that wrong?
그게 잘못인가요?
Uh, I mean, arguably there is a school of thought that would be to say that that a in inverted commas
제 생각에는 어떤 학파에서는 A는 인용 쉼표로 쳐선 안 된다고 말할
shouldn't count.
것 같아요
I mean, it's a stretch, but if we give it that, then we might say that saying that there are three
좀 억지스럽긴 하지만 그렇게 따지면 A가 세 개라고 하는
A's, uh, is uh, is not terrible.
것도 나쁘지 않다고 할 수 있죠
But then you'll see that it believes that one of those A's has come from the word sentence, which seems
하지만 비트는 문장 때문에 A가 나왔다고 믿죠 좀 실수처럼
like a bit of a gaffe.
보이지만요
Uh, so, uh, no, it's sadly oh, one preview is still our winner in this regard.
그래서, 아뇨, 슬프게도 이런 점에선 프리뷰 하나가 승자예요
Uh, so we can do more, more experiments.
실험을 더 할 수 있어요
But I think we should move on to cohere from, uh, the.
하지만 코어에서 코어로 넘어가는 게 좋겠어요
Sorry, this is Command Plus from cohere, Canadian AI company.
캐나다 인공지능 회사 코헤어의 커맨드 플러스인데요
It really focuses a lot on the knowledge that it has specific knowledge in different areas.
여러 분야에 대한 지식에 집중하는 거예요
Let's ask it that question.
그 질문을 해보죠
Compared to other frontier llms, what kinds of questions are you best at answering and compare it to
다른 지역과 비교했을 때 어떤 질문에 가장 잘 대답하고 다른 지역과 비교할 수 있나요?
So, um, what we get back?
Get in get it. 뭘 받게 되죠?
First of all, it says as an AI language model I'm designed to assist blah blah blah.
우선, 인공지능 언어 모델로서 보조를 위해 어쩌고저쩌고 설계되었어요
It gives some strengths, it gives some challenges, complimentary llms.
강점도 있고 도전도 있고 llm도 보너스로 주죠
Uh, so it gives a number of types of model, but it doesn't actually list the names of the models.
모델의 여러 유형을 제공하지만 모델의 이름을 나열하진 않아요
But it's still a perfectly decent answer, making making it clear that it doesn't have multimodal abilities.
하지만 그래도 정답입니다 다중 모듈 기능이 없다는 걸 확실히 보여 주죠
Uh, and so on.
뭐, 그런 거요
So it's a pretty good, thorough answer that demonstrates that it has resource to more information about
꽤 훌륭하고 철저한 답변이에요 이런 종류의 것에 대한 더 많은 정보를 위한 리소스가 있다는
this kind of thing.
걸 보여주죠
Uh, why don't we ask it?
직접 물어보죠
What does it feel like?
어떤 느낌이에요?
To be jealous.
질투하는 거요
See how that compares?
비교해 보세요
Uh, and again, you can see it's a really thorough.
정말 꼼꼼한 걸 볼 수 있어요
Really.
정말이에요
You can you can get that sense that it's able to draw on a wealth of knowledge.
풍부한 지식을 끌어다 쓸 수 있다는 느낌을 받을 수 있죠 get it
It's perhaps less of an expressive answer than we got from Claude, but I'd say that it appears to have
클로드가 준 답보다 표현력이 덜하지만 구조와
more sort of structure and detail and substance to it, uh, just based on a on a cursory look through.
세부 사항이 더 있는 것 같아요 대충 훑어본 결과죠
But but you should take some more time and see what you think.
하지만 좀 더 시간을 갖고 생각해 보세요
Uh, but it's, it's, it's clear that it's, it's good at this stuff.
하지만 확실히 이런 일을 잘하네요
And, you know, we might as well we're having some fun with this.
이왕이면 재미있게 하는 게 좋잖아요
Why don't we ask her, hear the question.
직접 물어보고 질문도 들어보죠
How many times does the letter A appear in this sentence?
A가 이 문장에 몇 번이나 나오죠?
And letter A appears 11 times in this sentence.
A는 이 문장에 11번 등장해요
There we go.
됐어요
Now we now we know.
이제 알게 됐네요
So again, uh, the the fact that that this platform is able to draw on a wealth of background knowledge
다시 말씀드리지만 이 플랫폼이 풍부한 배경 지식을 끌어다 쓸 수 있다는 사실은 그런 종류의 작업에는
doesn't help it with that kind of task.
도움이 안 되죠
And again, this is particularly picking on something which Llms can struggle with due to the way that
특히 림프관리자가 어려워하는 대상을 선택합니다 림프관리자는 훈련된
they are trained, uh, and, and the way that they run in inference mode.
방식과 추론 모드로 달리는 방식 때문이죠
All right.
좋아요
So that's a quick look at uh Gemini and Co here.
제미니와 코의 모습을 잠깐 봤는데요
And then the next time we'll, we'll look at the last two meta AI and perplexity.
다음 시간엔 마지막 두 개의 메타 인공지능과 당혹스러움을 보죠